like hospital-acquired infections. I believe this has got to be, in part, a building ecology problem. All right, I'm going to tell you one more story about this building. I am collaborating with Charlie Brown. He's an architect, and Charlie is deeply concerned about global climate change. He's dedicated his life to sustainable design. When he met me and realized that it was possible for him to study in a quantitative way how his design choices impacted the ecology and biology of this building, he got really excited, because it added a new dimension to what he did. He went from thinking just about energy to also starting to think about human health. He helped design some of the air handling systems in this building and the way it was ventilated. So what I'm first going to show you is air that we sampled outside of the building. What you're looking at is a signature of bacterial communities in the outdoor air, and how they vary over time. Next I'm going to show you what happened when we experimentally manipulated classrooms. We blocked them off at night so that they got no ventilation. A lot of buildings are operated this way, probably where you work, and companies do this to save money on their energy bill. What we found is that these rooms remained relatively stagnant until Saturday, when we opened the vents up again. When you walked into those rooms, they smelled really bad, and our data suggests that it had something to do with leaving behind the airborne bacterial soup from people the day before. Contrast this to rooms that were designed using a sustainable passive design strategy where air came in from the outside through louvers. In these rooms, the air tracked the outdoor air relatively well, and when Charlie saw this, he got really excited. He felt like he had made a good choice with the design process because it was both energy efficient and it washed away the building's resident microbial landscape. The examples that I just gave you are about architecture, but they're relevant to the design of anything. Imagine designing with the kinds of microbes that we want in a plane or on a phone. There's a new microbe, I just discovered it. It's called BLIS, and it's been shown to both ward off pathogens and give you good breath. Wouldn't it be awesome if we all had BLIS on our phones? A conscious approach to design, I'm calling it bioinformed design, and I think it's possible. Thank you. (Applause)
comme les infections nosocomiales. Je maintiens que c'est en partie un problème d'écologie de bâtiments. Bon, je vais vous raconter une autre histoire sur cet immeuble. Je collabore avec Charlie Brown. Charlie est architecte, et il est profondément préoccupé par le changement climatique mondial. Il a consacré sa vie au design durable. Quand on s'est rencontrés et qu'il s'est rendu compte qu'il lui serait possible d'étudier de manière quantitative l'influence de ses choix de conception sur l'écologie et la biologie de la construction, il s'est vraiment enthousiasmé, parce que ça ajoutait une dimension nouvelle à ce qu'il faisait. Il a cessé de réfléchir uniquement à l'énergie pour commencer à réfléchir à la santé humaine. Il a contribué à la conception de certains des systèmes de traitement d'air dans ce bâtiment et de la façon dont il était ventilé. Alors, ce que je vous montre d'abord c'est de l'air que nous avons échantillonné à l'extérieur du bâtiment. Ce que vous regardez est une signature des communautés bactériennes dans l'air extérieur, et comment elles varient dans le temps. Maintenant je vais vous montrer ce qui s'est passé lorsque nous avons manipulé expérimentalement les salles de classe. Nous avons bloqué leurs circuits d'air toute la nuit de sorte qu'elles ne puissent pas être ventilées. De nombreux bâtiments sont administrés de cette manière, probablement là où vous travaillez,